<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mtb on Janani Ravi</title>
    <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/tags/mtb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mtb on Janani Ravi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Janani Ravi, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jananiravi.github.io/tags/mtb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress response</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/project/stress-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/project/stress-response/</guid>
      <description>Research During my postdoctoral research at Rutgers University, I focused on using computational approaches to study various facets of host and pathogen biology including:
 delineating the molecular mechanism underlying a newly identified stress response operon in the tubercle bacterium involving the phage-shock-proteins (psp); unraveling the evolution of bacterial stress response systems (psp) across the tree of life using protein sequence-structure-function relationships; reconstructing and analyzing the mycobacterial sigma factor regulatory network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction and topological characterization of the sigma factor regulatory network of Mycobacterium tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2016/natcomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2016/natcomm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lipid metabolism &amp; TB</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/project/lipid-metabolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/project/lipid-metabolism/</guid>
      <description>Research In addition to stress-response systems on the pathogenic side, I studied some host responses to M. tuberculosis infection using computational approaches as well:
 characterizing the transcriptional response in infected macrophages under various small molecule perturbations using RNA-Seq analysis; understanding the dysregulation of lipid metabolism in M. tuberculosis-infected macrophages using dynamic Bayesian model and statistical analyses of heterogeneous single-cell populations.  Related publications  Lipid Metabolism and TB, in preparation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psp system of Mycobacterium tuberculosis integrates envelope stress-sensing and envelope-preserving functions</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2015/molmicro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2015/molmicro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting edge: Vitamin D regulates lipid metabolism in Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2014/jimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/publication/2014/jimm/</guid>
      <description>More detail can easily be written here using Markdown and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>