<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>compbio-bioinfo on Janani Ravi</title>
    <link>/tags/compbio-bioinfo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in compbio-bioinfo on Janani Ravi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Janani Ravi, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/compbio-bioinfo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Group</title>
      <link>/group/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/group/</guid>
      <description>PI Janani Ravi Pathobiology and Diagnostic Investigation, Michigan State University. GitHub | Twitter | Webpage Students           Lauren Sosinski Majors: Biochemistry &amp;amp; Biotechnology; Genomics and Molecular Genetics; Minor: CMSE GitHub; Twitter    Philip Calhoun Human Biology (pre-med) Drew Scholar; Honors College; Dean&amp;rsquo;s List; SROP fellowship GitHub; Twitter    Samuel Chen Computer Science Engineering Honors College; Dean&amp;rsquo;s List; State Scholarship GitHub    Phoebe Tuyishime Major: Nutritional Sciences; Minor: Global Public Health &amp;amp; Epidemiology Mastercard Foundation Scholar; Justin S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we do!</title>
      <link>/group/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/group/about/</guid>
      <description>Our research involves developing computational approaches that can leverage large-scale genomic data to gain actionable insights into infectious disease biology. Specifically, we focus on three key areas:
i) Identifying genomic signatures, functions, and mechanisms relevant to host-pathogen interactions, to enable understanding and guide diagnosis, ii) Unraveling molecular mechanisms common between genetic and infectious diseases, to guide targeted drug repurposing, and iii) Developing tools and resources for seamlessly relating sequence, structure, and function of genes/proteins in poorly characterized pathogens to enable and guide better prevention, diagnostic and treatment regimen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us!</title>
      <link>/joinus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/joinus/</guid>
      <description>Open positions Undergraduate Student Research We are looking for highly motivated and quantitatively-minded undergraduate students to work on a research project developing computational approaches to accelerate drug-/vaccine-target discovery against infectious diseases. Currently, we prefer students coming in with fellowships/scholarships (e.g., SROP, ENSURE, other department/college-level awards).
We are happy to train them in many aspects of data-intensive biology. A keen interest in bioinformatics, computational biology, statistics/biostatistics, computer science, genetics, or related fields, and prior programming experience in R, Python, Perl, and/or C/C++ would be a huge plus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Resources</title>
      <link>/post/2018/useful-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/useful-resources/</guid>
      <description>My posts with some #useful-resources.
Great posts | academic  The Awesomest 7-year Postdoc by Radhika Nagpal | Scientific American Matt Might’s Blog Modeler’s Hippocratic oath   Bioinformatics  Microbial Bioinformatics Starter Kit by Lauren Cowley Microbial genome annotation by Michael Eisen  Twitter thread &amp;amp; moment  Tools for bacterial comparative genomes by Holt lab   R  Git, GitHub and R R resources by Paul Vanderlaken Related post: R Tips and Tricks   Data Visualization  Plotting trees + data by Holt Lab   Blogdown, Hugo, Academic &amp;amp; R Markdown  Blogdown: Creating websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie Hugo  Hugo discussion forum  Hugo Academic by George Cushen  Academic  R Markdown Building your blog using blogdown by Marie Dussault   Blogging tips  Lifehacker 6 tips for low-cost academic blogging by Matt Might Ready to start your data science blog?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Stress Response</title>
      <link>/projects/stress-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/stress-response/</guid>
      <description>Summary During my postdoctoral research at Rutgers University, I focused on using computational approaches to study various facets of host and pathogen biology including:
 delineating the molecular mechanism underlying a newly identified stress response operon in the tubercle bacterium involving the phage-shock-proteins (psp); unraveling the evolution of bacterial stress response systems (psp) across the tree of life using protein sequence-structure-function relationships; reconstructing and analyzing the mycobacterial sigma factor regulatory network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies East Lansing</title>
      <link>/projects/rladies-eastlansing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/rladies-eastlansing/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies East Lansing Posts &amp;amp; Workshops</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>My posts with some useful resources
 Git, GitHub and R Modeler&amp;rsquo;s Hippocratic oath  Great posts | academic  The Awesomest 7-year Postdoc by Radhika Nagpal | Scientific American  Bioinformatics  Microbial Bioinformatics Starter Kit by Lauren Cowley Microbial genome annotation by Michael Eisen  Twitter thread &amp;amp; moment  Tools for bacterial comparative genomes by Holt lab  R  R resources by Paul Vanderlaken  Related post: R Tips and Tricks   Blogdown, Hugo, Academic &amp;amp; R Markdown  Blogdown: Creating websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie Hugo  Hugo discussion forum  Hugo Academic by George Cushen  Academic  R Markdown Building your blog using blogdown by Marie Dussault  Data Visualization  Plotting trees + data by Holt Lab  Blogging tips  Lifehacker 6 tips for low-cost academic blogging by Matt Might Ready to start your data science blog?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variations on a theme: evolution of the phage-shock-protein system in Actinobacteria</title>
      <link>/publication/2018/anto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018/anto/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction and topological characterization of the sigma factor regulatory network of Mycobacterium tuberculosis</title>
      <link>/publication/2016/natcomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2016/natcomm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TB &amp; Lipid metabolism</title>
      <link>/projects/lipid-metabolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/lipid-metabolism/</guid>
      <description>Summary In addition to stress-response systems on the pathogenic side, I studied some host responses to M. tuberculosis infection using computational approaches as well:
 characterizing the transcriptional response in infected macrophages under various small molecule perturbations using RNA-Seq analysis; understanding the dysregulation of lipid metabolism in M. tuberculosis-infected macrophages using dynamic Bayesian model and statistical analyses of heterogeneous single-cell populations.  Related publications  Lipid Metabolism and TB, in preparation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psp system of Mycobacterium tuberculosis integrates envelope stress-sensing and envelope-preserving functions</title>
      <link>/publication/2015/molmicro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2015/molmicro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting edge: Vitamin D regulates lipid metabolism in Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection</title>
      <link>/publication/2014/jimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2014/jimm/</guid>
      <description>More detail can easily be written here using Markdown and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>