<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on Janani Ravi</title>
    <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on Janani Ravi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Janani Ravi, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jananiravi.github.io/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>J1 visa waiver | How to obtain your NORI?</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/post/2017/j1-visa-waiver-nori/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/post/2017/j1-visa-waiver-nori/</guid>
      <description>About Me Why I’m writing this The initial process, where you read and imbibe! Helpful links:  Approximate order of key events &amp;amp; things-to-do Initial set of documents needed for the Indian Consulate attestation Documents to be sent to Indian Home Department Documents to be sent to the other two departments: List of documents  Addresses for mailing your packages TN State Department Regional Passport Office (RPO)  Additional documents required for police verification Main letters/documents Supporting documents  Final set of documents to be sent to the USCIS, Department of State Address for the package to be sent Tracking progress    About Me I’m Janani Ravi, currently at Michigan State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dedication to Ramanujan</title>
      <link>https://jananiravi.github.io/post/2016/ramanujan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jananiravi.github.io/post/2016/ramanujan/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Janani Ravi, Arjun Krishnan
Srinivasa Ramanujan has been noted as one of the classic ‘genius-mathematicians’ of all time! Hailing from the same state/country as him, Arjun Krishnan and I have always looked up to him &amp;amp; his elegant math as a source of inspiration right through our formative years!
The Movie Recent movie that has drastically increased Ramanujan’s international visibility The Man Who Knew Infinity by Matthew Brown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>